Github: https://github.com/dsanderson90

Email: sanderdj90@gmail.com Website: davidsanderson.dev

DAVID SANDERSON / FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Albuquerque-based Fullstack Developer with a strong passion for designing, building, and deploying custom websites/software applications. Most familiar with the React(GatsbyJS!) but also proficient with Node, Express, C#, CSS, HTML, PHP(Laravel) and willing to learn new technologies . Resilient and curious problem solver with 2 years of development experience, excellent interpersonal skills, and the tenacity to solve difficult problems.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer, iTeam Consulting

February 2020 - Present

- Migrate multiple legacy websites to the JAM stack using GatsbyJS.
- Maintain and regularly update legacy ASP.NET Web applications (MVC 5.0 and Razor Pages).
- Proactive site maintenance to Wordpress sites (update content, plugins, and create monthly backups).
- Migrate WordPress sites to new hosting providers and update DNS records.
- Create wireframes using Figma inspired by a style guide
- Implement designs I create or am provided.
- Created a Gatsby application that sources data from Sharepoint Lists to programmatically create web pages.
- Write units tests using Jest and xUnit.

TECHNOLOGIES USED: React, Gatsby, Netlify, NetlifyCMS, KeystoneJS, Ghost, Jest, GQL, C#, Docker, TailwindCSS, FileZilla, Emotion, Wordpress, various ORMs

Resident Web Developer, <u>ActivateNM</u> (Startup Incubator)

October 2019 - February 2020

- Provided technical support and consultation to early-stage startups going through the accelerator program.
- Drafted and executed project charters. Designed and deployed 3 websites(Gatsby and Wordpress sites) and 1 database.

TECHNOLOGIES USED: React, Gatsby, GQL, WordPress, MySQL, MySQL Workbench

Owner, Closure Consulting LLC — Self-Employed

October 2019 - Present

 Design, develop, and deliver high-quality, custom websites and web applications to clients throughout New Mexico.

Freelance Web Developer — Self-Employed

December 2018 - October 2019

- Helped local business owners develop or revamp their online presence and messaging.
- Designed and deployed custom websites for various clients, assisted with maintenance, updates, and hosting.

Deep Dive Coding Bootcamp, CNM Ingenuity — Junior Web Developer

October 2018 - December 2018

- Intensive 10-week Bootcamp. 500+ hours training in JavaScript, PHP, Angular, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, GitHub.
- Created a personal portfolio website and worked on a team capstone project (505 Foodtruck Finder) which utilized Angular and Google Maps to track food truck locations.

Realty One of New Mexico — Associate Broker

July 2017 - October 2018

- Guided prospective homebuyers through home buying process. Successfully closed 3+ transactions.
- Conducted Facebook marketing campaigns to target first time homebuyers.

PR Newswire — Inside Sales Representative

August 2014 - August 2017

- Managed account base of 350+ accounts using the Salesforce CRM. Organisations included non-profits, agencies, and small to medium size businesses.
- Consistently met or exceeded 100% of sales goal and cultivated relationships with clients.
- Helped clients hone their messaging and create a result-oriented content strategy that targets their audience.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO — **Bachelor's of Science**, Evolutionary Anthropology